<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Part 2 on msteenhagen</title>
    <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/tags/part-2/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Part 2 on msteenhagen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 M. Steenhagen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://msteenhagen.github.io/tags/part-2/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Causation</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018cau/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018cau/</guid>
      <description>Course description The relation between causes and effects is typically taken to have a direction (it&amp;rsquo;s asymmetric). Whenever C is a cause of E, then E is not a cause of C. Moreover, this directionality seems aligned with both the temporal arrow and with patterns of practical deliberation. How do we explain this feature? Not all philosophical analyses of causation capture the concept of causal direction in the same way, if they capture it at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Realism and Anti-Realism</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018rea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018rea/</guid>
      <description>Course description These four lectures will discuss Michael Dummett&amp;rsquo;s and Hilary Putnam&amp;rsquo;s objections to metaphysical realism.
Where and when Weeks 1-4, Friday 10-11, Lecture Block Room 7
Lecture 1: Realism This lecture introduces the discussion about realism. We can distinguish three forms realism can take: metaphysical, epistemological, and semantic. Metaphysical realism has been criticised from an epistemological angle by idealist philosophers. Semantic realism has been the target of recent discussions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causation</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016cau/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016cau/</guid>
      <description>_This is the course page for a course taught in 2017. For the 2018 version, please consult: http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018cau
Course description The relation between causes and effects is typically taken to be asymmetric. Whenever C is a cause of E, then E is not a cause of C. But how do we explain this feature? What kind of asymmetry is this? Not all philosophical analyses of causation capture the concept of causal asymmetry equally well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intentionality and Representation</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016ire/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016ire/</guid>
      <description>Course description Can the intentionality of the mind be explained by a naturalistic conception of the world? Intentional mental states are those that are ‘about’ things in the world. This is sometimes described as their having representational content. The intentionality of mental states has been considered to be a defining characteristic of the mind and of mental life. And many of the people who think this also accept that the mind is a natural phenomenon.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>