<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Teachings on msteenhagen</title>
    <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Teachings on msteenhagen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 M. Steenhagen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Qualities</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2019qua/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2019qua/</guid>
      <description>Course description These four lectures will talk about qualities. We will discuss the distinction between primary and secondary qualities, dispositional theories of colour, response-dependence concepts, the missing explanation argument, and a more simple view of colour or secondary qualities more generally.
Suggested general reading  Lawrence Nolan, ed. Primary and Secondary Qualities: The Historical and Ongoing Debate (Oxford: OUP, 2011), pp. 136-157. (Introduction and chapters by Pasnau, Downing, and Ayers) Wright, Crispin (1988), &amp;lsquo;Moral Values, Projection and Secondary Qualities&amp;rsquo; Proceedings of the Aristotelian Society 26, 1-26.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dualism and Functionalism</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2019dua/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2019dua/</guid>
      <description>Course description These lectures will introduce the mind-body problem: the problem of the relation between mind and matter, or mind and body. We will consider the nature of mental life and physical processes, and the competing doctrines of dualism and materialism/physicalism. The nature of mind poses a dilemma for philosophy. If the mind is not physical, then how can it have effects in the physical world? But if the mind is physical, then how can we explain consciousness?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verificationism</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2019ver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2019ver/</guid>
      <description>Course description What is the connection between the meaning of a sentence and its verification conditions? This series of four lectures will present the motivations and fate of the early-twentieth century verification theory of meaning.
Feel free to contact me at ms2416@cam.ac.uk if you have any suggestions, questions, or comments about this course.
General reading  AYER, A.J., Language, Truth and Logic. 2nd ed. (London: Gollancz, 1946), Introduction &amp;amp; ch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Conditionals</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018cda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018cda/</guid>
      <description>Course description These lectures will introduce the philosophical discussion about conditionals. For this, we need to ask what the relation is between the meaning of formal languages and the meaning of natural languages.
Online resources Outlines and handouts will be made available on:
http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018cda/
Where and when Monday 3-4pm. Lecture Block Room 1.
Lecture 1: Meaning and natural language This lecture will discuss Grice&amp;rsquo;s theory of sentence meaning and communicative intentions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind-reading</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018mre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018mre/</guid>
      <description>Course description These lectures will introduce the problem of other minds and discuss the philosophical debate about mind-reading.
Online resources Outlines and handouts will be made available on:
http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018mre/
Where and when Monday 1-2pm. Lecture Block Room 12.
Lecture 1: Sympathy, empathy and the problem of other minds This lecture will introduce a history of thinking about empathy and the problem of other minds. A central argument in this discussion is the Argument from Analogy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Induction and Causation</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018inc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018inc/</guid>
      <description>Course description These lectures will introduce the problems of induction and the metaphysics of causation (or causality, or cause and effect).
Online resources Outlines and handouts will be made available on:
http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018inc/
Where and when Friday 10-11. Lecture Block Room 1.
Lecture 1: Hume and the problem of induction In this lecture I introduce the idea of induction, and discuss David Hume&amp;rsquo;s problem of induction.
(Download handout here)
Lecture 2: Goodman&amp;rsquo;s new riddle of induction In this lecture I discuss Nelson Goodman&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;new riddle&amp;rsquo; of induction, and will contrast it with the old riddle formulated by David Hume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Necessity, Analyticity, A Priority</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018naa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018naa/</guid>
      <description>Course description This course will introduce several key distinctions: analytic / synthetic; a priori / a posteriori; and necessary / contingent. It will cover the syllabus materials on Analyticity, A Priority, and Necessity (the first section of Paper 3, Meaning). Feel free to contact me at ms2416@cam.ac.uk if you have any suggestions, questions, or comments about this course.
General reading An interesting and readable introductory textbook is: Sybil Wolfram (1989), Philosophical Logic: An Introduction, Oxford: Routledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perception</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018per/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018per/</guid>
      <description>Course description In these lectures I will discuss different philosophical views of the nature of perceptual experience, and analyze central objections.
Where and when Friday 3-4pm, Lecture Room 2 (Sidgwick Site Lecture Block)
Lecture 1: Naive realism Naive realism is the view that perceptual experience fundamentally is a presentation (to us) of familiar, mind-independent objects in our environment. It is motivated by the phenomenology of perception. Perception&amp;mdash;the Naive Realist maintains&amp;mdash;seems to be a presentation of those objects, and without a reason to think otherwise we can just take that appearance at face value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consciousness</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018con/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018con/</guid>
      <description>Course description In this series of advanced seminars we will discuss six key contributions to the philosophical debate about the nature of consciousness. The reading list covers the Part II syllabus materials on Consciousness for the Tripos paper in Philosophy of Mind. Besides Part II students, students on the Philosophy MPhil programme are welcome to attend.
Feel free to contact me at ms2416@cam.ac.uk if you have any suggestions, questions, or comments about this course.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theories of Meaning</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018tom/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018tom/</guid>
      <description>Course description This course will discuss four key moments twentieth century philosophy of language and logic. It will cover the Part 1b syllabus materials on Theories of Meaning for the paper in Logic. Feel free to contact me at ms2416@cam.ac.uk if you have any suggestions, questions, or comments about this course.
General reading An good and comprehensive textbook is: Alexander Miller (2007), Philosophy of Language (2nd ed.), London: Routledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Qualities</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018qua/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Feb 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018qua/</guid>
      <description>Course description These four lectures will talk about qualities. We will discuss the distinction between primary and secondary qualities, dispositional theories of colour, response-dependence concepts, the missing explanation argument, and a more simple view of colour or secondary qualities more generally.
Suggested Reading I will add some suggested reading in due course
Where and when Friday 2-3pm, Lecture Block Room 2
Lecture 1: Drawing distinctions: Primary and Secondary Qualities How do we draw the distinction between primary and secondary qualities?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causation</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018cau/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018cau/</guid>
      <description>Course description The relation between causes and effects is typically taken to have a direction (it&amp;rsquo;s asymmetric). Whenever C is a cause of E, then E is not a cause of C. Moreover, this directionality seems aligned with both the temporal arrow and with patterns of practical deliberation. How do we explain this feature? Not all philosophical analyses of causation capture the concept of causal direction in the same way, if they capture it at all.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Realism and Anti-Realism</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018rea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018rea/</guid>
      <description>Course description These four lectures will discuss Michael Dummett&amp;rsquo;s and Hilary Putnam&amp;rsquo;s objections to metaphysical realism.
Where and when Weeks 1-4, Friday 10-11, Lecture Block Room 7
Lecture 1: Realism This lecture introduces the discussion about realism. We can distinguish three forms realism can take: metaphysical, epistemological, and semantic. Metaphysical realism has been criticised from an epistemological angle by idealist philosophers. Semantic realism has been the target of recent discussions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causation</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2017cau1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2017cau1a/</guid>
      <description>Course description These lectures will introduce the metaphysics of causation (or causality, or cause and effect). After a brief introduction to the topic, and some historical background, we will consider the concept of causal necessity and then look at David Hume’s view of causation, followed by David Lewis’s counterfactual theory, and the main objections to it.
Online resources Outlines and handouts will be made available on:
http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2017cau1a/
Where and when Thursday 11-12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophical Logic</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2017plo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2017plo/</guid>
      <description>Course description This lecture course will introduce several key concepts in the philosophy of language and logic. It will cover the syllabus materials on Philosophical Logic (Section B of the paper in Logic). Feel free to contact me at ms2416@cam.ac.uk if you have any suggestions, questions, or comments about this course.
General reading An interesting and readable introductory textbook is: Sybil Wolfram (1989), Philosophical Logic: An Introduction, Oxford: Routledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leibniz</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2017lei/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2017lei/</guid>
      <description>Course description Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz (1646, Leipzig – 1716, Hanover) was one of the last Renaissance intellectuals (&amp;lsquo;a universal mind&amp;rsquo;). He made lasting contributions to philosophy, mathematics, theology, jurisprudence, politics, technology, and architecture. This lecture course will offer an overview of some central ideas in his philosophy. Feel free to contact me at ms2416@cam.ac.uk if you have any suggestions, questions, or comments about this course.
General reading  Discourse on Metaphysics Monadology New Essays on Human Understanding (especially books 1-2)  Online resources Handouts will be made available on: http://msteenhagen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perception</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2017pcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2017pcp/</guid>
      <description>Course description In these lectures I will discuss different philosophical views of the nature of perceptual experience, and analyze central objections.
Where and when Friday 3-4pm, Lecture Room 4 (Sidgwick Site Lecture Block)
Lecture 1: Naive realism and the argument from hallucination Naive realism is the view that perceptual experience fundamentally is a presentation (to us) of familiar, mind-independent objects in our environment. It is motivated by the phenomenology of perception.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Causation</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016cau/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016cau/</guid>
      <description>_This is the course page for a course taught in 2017. For the 2018 version, please consult: http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018cau
Course description The relation between causes and effects is typically taken to be asymmetric. Whenever C is a cause of E, then E is not a cause of C. But how do we explain this feature? What kind of asymmetry is this? Not all philosophical analyses of causation capture the concept of causal asymmetry equally well.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intentionality and Representation</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016ire/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016ire/</guid>
      <description>Course description Can the intentionality of the mind be explained by a naturalistic conception of the world? Intentional mental states are those that are ‘about’ things in the world. This is sometimes described as their having representational content. The intentionality of mental states has been considered to be a defining characteristic of the mind and of mental life. And many of the people who think this also accept that the mind is a natural phenomenon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind and Matter</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016mam/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016mam/</guid>
      <description>Course description These lectures will introduce the mind-body problem: the problem of the relation between mind and matter, or mind and body. We will consider the nature of mental life and physical processes, and the competing doctrines of dualism and materialism/physicalism. The nature of mind poses a dilemma for philosophy. If the mind is not physical, then how can it have effects in the physical world? But if the mind is physical, then how can we explain consciousness?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind Dependence</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016mde/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016mde/</guid>
      <description>Course description In this course we will consider how philosophers have defended the mind-dependence of some or all objects of experience. In its most extreme forms, such defences of mind-dependence result in Idealistic views about the nature of reality as we know it. But the more widely accepted distinction between primary and secondary qualities of experience equally reduces important features of the world to mere modifications of mind or experience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophical Logic (2016)</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016plo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016plo/</guid>
      <description>Course description This course will introduce several key concepts in the philosophy of language and logic. It will cover the syllabus materials on Philosophical Logic (Section B of the paper in Logic). Feel free to contact me at ms2416@cam.ac.uk if you have any suggestions, questions, or comments about this course.
General reading An interesting and readable introductory textbook is: Sybil Wolfram (1989), Philosophical Logic: An Introduction, Oxford: Routledge.
Online resources Outlines and handouts will be made available on: http://msteenhagen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persons</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016per/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016per/</guid>
      <description>Course description These four lectures will consider the nature and persistence of persons over time. A particular focus will be on the recent debate about Animalism. The lectures will cover the Part 2 syllabus materials on Persons for the paper on Metaphysics. Feel free to contact me at ms2416@cam.ac.uk if you have any suggestions, questions, or comments about this course.
General reading Those looking for an introduction may consult the Stanford Encyclopedia, which has a useful entry on Animalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theories of Meaning</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016tom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016tom/</guid>
      <description>Course description This course will discuss four key moments twentieth century philosophy of language and logic. It will cover the Part 1b syllabus materials on Theories of Meaning for the paper in Logic. Feel free to contact me at ms2416@cam.ac.uk if you have any suggestions, questions, or comments about this course.
General reading An good and comprehensive textbook is: Alexander Miller (2007), Philosophy of Language (2nd ed.), London: Routledge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>