<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Lent 2019 on msteenhagen</title>
    <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/tags/lent-2019/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Lent 2019 on msteenhagen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 M. Steenhagen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://msteenhagen.github.io/tags/lent-2019/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Qualities</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2019qua/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2019qua/</guid>
      <description>Course description These four lectures will talk about qualities. We will discuss the distinction between primary and secondary qualities, dispositional theories of colour, response-dependence concepts, the missing explanation argument, and a more simple view of colour or secondary qualities more generally.
Suggested general reading  Lawrence Nolan, ed. Primary and Secondary Qualities: The Historical and Ongoing Debate (Oxford: OUP, 2011), pp. 136-157. (Introduction and chapters by Pasnau, Downing, and Ayers) Wright, Crispin (1988), &amp;lsquo;Moral Values, Projection and Secondary Qualities&amp;rsquo; Proceedings of the Aristotelian Society 26, 1-26.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dualism and Functionalism</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2019dua/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2019dua/</guid>
      <description>Course description These lectures will introduce the mind-body problem: the problem of the relation between mind and matter, or mind and body. We will consider the nature of mental life and physical processes, and the competing doctrines of dualism and materialism/physicalism. The nature of mind poses a dilemma for philosophy. If the mind is not physical, then how can it have effects in the physical world? But if the mind is physical, then how can we explain consciousness?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Verificationism</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2019ver/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2019ver/</guid>
      <description>Course description What is the connection between the meaning of a sentence and its verification conditions? This series of four lectures will present the motivations and fate of the early-twentieth century verification theory of meaning.
Feel free to contact me at ms2416@cam.ac.uk if you have any suggestions, questions, or comments about this course.
General reading  AYER, A.J., Language, Truth and Logic. 2nd ed. (London: Gollancz, 1946), Introduction &amp;amp; ch.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>