<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michaelmas 2017 on msteenhagen</title>
    <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/tags/michaelmas-2017/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Michaelmas 2017 on msteenhagen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 M. Steenhagen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://msteenhagen.github.io/tags/michaelmas-2017/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Causation</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2017cau1a/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2017cau1a/</guid>
      <description>Course description These lectures will introduce the metaphysics of causation (or causality, or cause and effect). After a brief introduction to the topic, and some historical background, we will consider the concept of causal necessity and then look at David Hume’s view of causation, followed by David Lewis’s counterfactual theory, and the main objections to it.
Online resources Outlines and handouts will be made available on:
http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2017cau1a/
Where and when Thursday 11-12.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophical Logic</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2017plo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2017plo/</guid>
      <description>Course description This lecture course will introduce several key concepts in the philosophy of language and logic. It will cover the syllabus materials on Philosophical Logic (Section B of the paper in Logic). Feel free to contact me at ms2416@cam.ac.uk if you have any suggestions, questions, or comments about this course.
General reading An interesting and readable introductory textbook is: Sybil Wolfram (1989), Philosophical Logic: An Introduction, Oxford: Routledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Leibniz</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2017lei/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2017lei/</guid>
      <description>Course description Gottfried Wilhelm Leibniz (1646, Leipzig – 1716, Hanover) was one of the last Renaissance intellectuals (&amp;lsquo;a universal mind&amp;rsquo;). He made lasting contributions to philosophy, mathematics, theology, jurisprudence, politics, technology, and architecture. This lecture course will offer an overview of some central ideas in his philosophy. Feel free to contact me at ms2416@cam.ac.uk if you have any suggestions, questions, or comments about this course.
General reading  Discourse on Metaphysics Monadology New Essays on Human Understanding (especially books 1-2)  Online resources Handouts will be made available on: http://msteenhagen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perception</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2017pcp/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2017pcp/</guid>
      <description>Course description In these lectures I will discuss different philosophical views of the nature of perceptual experience, and analyze central objections.
Where and when Friday 3-4pm, Lecture Room 4 (Sidgwick Site Lecture Block)
Lecture 1: Naive realism and the argument from hallucination Naive realism is the view that perceptual experience fundamentally is a presentation (to us) of familiar, mind-independent objects in our environment. It is motivated by the phenomenology of perception.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>