<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michaelmas 2016 on msteenhagen</title>
    <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/tags/michaelmas-2016/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Michaelmas 2016 on msteenhagen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 M. Steenhagen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://msteenhagen.github.io/tags/michaelmas-2016/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Philosophical Logic (2016)</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016plo/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016plo/</guid>
      <description>Course description This course will introduce several key concepts in the philosophy of language and logic. It will cover the syllabus materials on Philosophical Logic (Section B of the paper in Logic). Feel free to contact me at ms2416@cam.ac.uk if you have any suggestions, questions, or comments about this course.
General reading An interesting and readable introductory textbook is: Sybil Wolfram (1989), Philosophical Logic: An Introduction, Oxford: Routledge.
Online resources Outlines and handouts will be made available on: http://msteenhagen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Persons</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016per/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016per/</guid>
      <description>Course description These four lectures will consider the nature and persistence of persons over time. A particular focus will be on the recent debate about Animalism. The lectures will cover the Part 2 syllabus materials on Persons for the paper on Metaphysics. Feel free to contact me at ms2416@cam.ac.uk if you have any suggestions, questions, or comments about this course.
General reading Those looking for an introduction may consult the Stanford Encyclopedia, which has a useful entry on Animalism.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Theories of Meaning</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016tom/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2016tom/</guid>
      <description>Course description This course will discuss four key moments twentieth century philosophy of language and logic. It will cover the Part 1b syllabus materials on Theories of Meaning for the paper in Logic. Feel free to contact me at ms2416@cam.ac.uk if you have any suggestions, questions, or comments about this course.
General reading An good and comprehensive textbook is: Alexander Miller (2007), Philosophy of Language (2nd ed.), London: Routledge.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>