<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Michaelmas 2018 on msteenhagen</title>
    <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/tags/michaelmas-2018/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Michaelmas 2018 on msteenhagen</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2019 M. Steenhagen</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://msteenhagen.github.io/tags/michaelmas-2018/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Conditionals</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018cda/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018cda/</guid>
      <description>Course description These lectures will introduce the philosophical discussion about conditionals. For this, we need to ask what the relation is between the meaning of formal languages and the meaning of natural languages.
Online resources Outlines and handouts will be made available on:
http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018cda/
Where and when Monday 3-4pm. Lecture Block Room 1.
Lecture 1: Meaning and natural language This lecture will discuss Grice&amp;rsquo;s theory of sentence meaning and communicative intentions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind-reading</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018mre/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018mre/</guid>
      <description>Course description These lectures will introduce the problem of other minds and discuss the philosophical debate about mind-reading.
Online resources Outlines and handouts will be made available on:
http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018mre/
Where and when Monday 1-2pm. Lecture Block Room 12.
Lecture 1: Sympathy, empathy and the problem of other minds This lecture will introduce a history of thinking about empathy and the problem of other minds. A central argument in this discussion is the Argument from Analogy.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Induction and Causation</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018inc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018inc/</guid>
      <description>Course description These lectures will introduce the problems of induction and the metaphysics of causation (or causality, or cause and effect).
Online resources Outlines and handouts will be made available on:
http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018inc/
Where and when Friday 10-11. Lecture Block Room 1.
Lecture 1: Hume and the problem of induction In this lecture I introduce the idea of induction, and discuss David Hume&amp;rsquo;s problem of induction.
(Download handout here)
Lecture 2: Goodman&amp;rsquo;s new riddle of induction In this lecture I discuss Nelson Goodman&amp;rsquo;s &amp;lsquo;new riddle&amp;rsquo; of induction, and will contrast it with the old riddle formulated by David Hume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Necessity, Analyticity, A Priority</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018naa/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018naa/</guid>
      <description>Course description This course will introduce several key distinctions: analytic / synthetic; a priori / a posteriori; and necessary / contingent. It will cover the syllabus materials on Analyticity, A Priority, and Necessity (the first section of Paper 3, Meaning). Feel free to contact me at ms2416@cam.ac.uk if you have any suggestions, questions, or comments about this course.
General reading An interesting and readable introductory textbook is: Sybil Wolfram (1989), Philosophical Logic: An Introduction, Oxford: Routledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Perception</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018per/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Oct 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018per/</guid>
      <description>Course description In these lectures I will discuss different philosophical views of the nature of perceptual experience, and analyze central objections.
Where and when Friday 3-4pm, Lecture Room 2 (Sidgwick Site Lecture Block)
Lecture 1: Naive realism Naive realism is the view that perceptual experience fundamentally is a presentation (to us) of familiar, mind-independent objects in our environment. It is motivated by the phenomenology of perception. Perception&amp;mdash;the Naive Realist maintains&amp;mdash;seems to be a presentation of those objects, and without a reason to think otherwise we can just take that appearance at face value.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Consciousness</title>
      <link>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018con/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://msteenhagen.github.io/teaching/2018con/</guid>
      <description>Course description In this series of advanced seminars we will discuss six key contributions to the philosophical debate about the nature of consciousness. The reading list covers the Part II syllabus materials on Consciousness for the Tripos paper in Philosophy of Mind. Besides Part II students, students on the Philosophy MPhil programme are welcome to attend.
Feel free to contact me at ms2416@cam.ac.uk if you have any suggestions, questions, or comments about this course.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>